PAUL: Alright. Please let me know, are you guys able to see it? Because somewhere I got an alert that the recording is stopped.
PAUL: Hello, everyone.
PAUL: Please let me know that, if there is connection issue.
PAUL: Because in my case, it told that recording got stopped, so really, like, everyone in the session
PAUL: Alright, recording is stopped, yes, we can hear you. Alright, fine.
PAUL: I thought I got DC.
PAUL: Now let's, move in the next phases. So, this part I have already discussed very specifically, the VLM pipeline. It's the same piece of code, really, nothing various which is fancy, the same thing that I have done it, by taking, through multiple PDFs.
PAUL: Okay. The same piece of code, really. There is nothing that I have done. Now comes the main part, which is basically the lang chain integration with Docklin.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part, even, like, very specifically, Dockling has a lot of other features with respect to chunking and other things, but right now, our main part was parsing, so very specifically, we have focused on that. But there are other functionalities also, so if I just go through…
PAUL: Doclinks GitHub, okay? So, docklings, github.io, docklings document, okay?
PAUL: So, I'm just showing you, because I really, like, if you are going to integrate in your… So, right now, you can see, this is the number one report, bit of trending.
PAUL: Hashtag, one repo of the day. Really, it works good. Okay, now there are a lot of things with respect to installation, pretty much standard stuff that you can do. Integrations is the main part, so LandChain, Langflow, Llama Indus, Haystack, Cree UI, so majorly everywhere, I can say, there is available integration.
PAUL: Then comes with respect to a few examples which have been provided. A quick start examples are there. Okay, a few major concepts with respect to exactly how DocLink was built, the Docklink document and the Docklink architecture with different type of backends.
PAUL: Now, really, like, this is not so much important that I feel, because you guys won't be building Docklink, rather than you will be directly consuming it. But if you want, okay, or if you want to do some contribution, so you can check this out. Now, the core part that comes is this examples part.
PAUL: In these examples, if you really look into, like, why they love it, so conversion examples ranging from simple conversion to markdown, export of figures and tables to VLM and audio pipelines, because when I'll be working with multimodal data, probably
PAUL: we have a specific module in your course. I'll be talking much more about focusing on multi-mode data, like performing tasks like image captioning. It means that in a PDF, if you have the image, you need to do some type of captioning operation and bring it back into your original document.
PAUL: Because directly image, you cannot bring it. So, probably, through text, you have to do. So, those type of tasks, very specifically, I'll be talking about. In multimodal phase.
PAUL: But for now, various rare examples based on Langchain, different vector data, so really, do you think that these things matters to us for a data parsing framework? I don't think so. If you're really working with data parsing, neither Langchain, neither Llama Index, neither VectorDB matters to me.
PAUL: Because that is a totally different task that I feel, totally independent task.
PAUL: Okay, examples of serialization and chunking, including user-defined customization. So, yes, in docklinks also, you do have, like, few types of chunker, like hybrid chunking is there, hierarchical chunking, but right now, we are not talking about chunking, it's much more about parsing. So, very specifically, I've kept it.
PAUL: Okay, now, can you see here, like, visual grounding with some picture annotations? These things much more, we'll be talking with respect to the multimodal classes, how to handle with images much more.
PAUL: Yeah, so these are the major ones.
PAUL: With respect to information extraction, so, like, this also, at any point of time, if you want any use case, like, very specifically within a document, okay, you want to extract only a certain part, and the rest of the part you don't want.
PAUL: See, in this particular type of cases, also, you can actually focus here. So, majorly, I've seen people, what they do, they will convert it into an OCR. On top of OCR, they will apply, on top of the results of the OCR, I've seen people applying records.
PAUL: the bare minimum solution. Anybody has worked on that? First, apply OCR on top of the results of OCR, apply a simple trick. That, I have seen, like, more than 80% of the people doing it.
PAUL: Actually, for these type of tasks, you need to define entities.
PAUL: Okay, now, I know that's a totally different discussion, but based on entity-based approach, it becomes much easier to identify stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so these are a few of the, I can say, the options that you have, and really, you can test it out. It's really, really famous. For the past 4 months, I've been tracking this project, I feel that it's really good.
PAUL: Okay, now with respect to coming soon, you can actually look into what are the things that are,
PAUL: Coming new, okay, so, like, chart understanding.
PAUL: Okay, complex chemistry, understanding molecular structures, metadata extraction. Okay, these type of supports will come going forward. Then, anybody knows about, Heron layout module?
PAUL: Here on Layout Module.
PAUL: Alright, this is also if somebody is working. First time working with respect to parsing, then comes. This is a pretty new concept.
PAUL: Now, these are the major things, okay, that we have talked about, because I felt at Granite dockly.
PAUL: And this is very important, because at the end of the day, the models which IBM Research has provided us, they work really good. So this Granite Docklink model is one of my favorite models, very specifically if I'm working with Docklink, but again, VLM-based approach.
PAUL: So, at any point of time, visual language models.
PAUL: You know what is the con, okay? Which is basically, the response time of the model will be always towards the higher side.
PAUL: Alright, now, let's do the integration with LanChain. So, guys, in Langchain, you need a package, LanChain-docling. Please install the package, and let me know that whether you do a pip show, it is available or not, in your system. Docling.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, you can do an UVPIP install based on whatever the version, and you can do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, I hope everybody has done it. Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, a few things with respect to your Langchen integration. So, directly, you have this particular module of LangChen underscore Docklink. Import Docklink loader.
PAUL: Okay? Similarly, then, LanChain Doppler link loader, export type. So, what type of export? Because, the main purpose of using LANCHEN, generally, we focus on those export types, as I have told you. Generally, like, my favorite is a markdown, similarly, people work with JSON, okay?
PAUL: Now, here, the PDF URL that I have passed, then I need to define the loader, okay? So, the docklink loader.
PAUL: And here, I'll be passing the file path, which is basically the PDF URL, and export type physical to chunks. So, directly, export type.chunks, it means that it will perform the chunking operation also.
PAUL: Okay, now this chunk, I will pass it in the next level.
PAUL: So, like, directly through, like, the LanChain Dockling integration, you can perform a chunking operation also, because in Dockling, there are few chunkers. I think majorly three types of chunkers that support the hybrid chunker, hierarchical chunker.
PAUL: And the other one is, I think, the name Junker is there.
PAUL: Okay? So, the core idea is you read the document and you convert it into chunks, directly through Lanshan DocLink integration.
PAUL: Once you have this, then in the next step is to load the document, because this is the part with respect to initialization.
PAUL: Okay, then the idea is to load all those chunks inside this particular docs variable.
PAUL: Okay, so… if I try to run this…
PAUL: Okay, again, a very similar pipeline, just like Dockline, that will be initialized.
PAUL: Yes, by default, those things are handled very cheap.
PAUL: I've told you the options. Always enable those options, even if you don't enable it for the table, by default, it will be taken.
PAUL: Okay, but for table extraction, you have to do that, one. And OCR engines, just remember, by default, it is the Rapid OCR, but try to stick to EasyOCR. I feel EZ OCR is a better project as compared to Rapid OCRs.
PAUL: Alright, so right now, based on that particular initialization, the total number of chunks, okay, and the document, so you can see here, loaded 41 chunks.
PAUL: So, very specifically, I have not applied any type of, like, chunking mechanism.
PAUL: Okay? So, for me, it's 41. Okay, for others, is it 44?
PAUL: I don't know, like, this number might, change.
PAUL: Okay, because right now, just be sure I'm using… based on the EDF, PDF that I provided.
PAUL: Okay, some people are telling… okay. Few people are telling 41, 41, 41, in my case, also 4T1.
PAUL: Yes, only one told 44. Really, please have it checked.
PAUL: Okay, Gaganda was getting 14, 9.
PAUL: Really, it is based on the version, because actually, it should throw you the same result at the end of the day.
PAUL: So, I'll feel that. Alright, fine. Probably using, because majorly, everybody's getting 41, so 4T1, I will take that into account.
PAUL: Now, in the next step with respect to the document chunk part, okay, so this is basically the first chunk that we are doing.
PAUL: Okay, and this is the metadata. Okay, so… this is the source…
PAUL: Then the schema, the version, the doc items, all this information that comes.
PAUL: from the archive PDF, because the releaser is archived, and based on that, how archive has maintained the metadata for this particular PDF document, we'll be getting all those information.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this time, returns the full document as a markdown. So, majorly, you guys have worked with export type markdown.
PAUL: Okay, in our previous examples, also, export type Markdown. My favorite type is much more export to markdown.
PAUL: Okay, and rather than, like,
PAUL: directly applying chunking, okay? It's not my preference. My preference is always saving to markdown, because any type of strategy with respect to chunking works better with respect to Markdown price.
PAUL: as compared to any other PDF files, if I'm talking about docx files, XLS files, okay? So, really, it doesn't work so much good.
PAUL: So, right here, what I'll be passing, directly the information, and based on that, I'll be getting the information with respect to the PDF.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, the first 500 characters that will be looted.
PAUL: Rahul, Ali, if I want to use a recursive? Yes, do it. Save the file in a Markdown format, apply recursive chunking. As simple as that, Rahul.
PAUL: Alright, now, in the next step.
PAUL: I think the part with respect to, okay, the dockling loader markdown format, we have done the extraction.
PAUL: Now, some custom converters, okay, that I have kept it. Few options are there, okay, but, really. Now, so, by default, majorly, I feel that at every point of time, do you think that you need tables, okay, or OCR and a bit?
PAUL: Okay, so by default settings, I prefer that you should not use any type of OCR, okay, and directly, because right now, what I'm doing, I'm using
PAUL: few part of the Docklinks, and I'm doing the integration with LangChain and DocLinkLooter. Okay, so right now, if you remember the old syntax of docklink.com, so here you define exactly what type of pipeline, based on that you select, like, I have taken the option of do OCR and do table structure.
PAUL: And then, based on that, the custom converter. See, the name I have given, custom converter, it… you can think about a simple converter. The idea is that to pass this specific converting instructions that you can specifically define in Docklink. Okay, now through your custom loader, you can actually pass it.
PAUL: Now, this is one good thing. So, this is where the integration of Dockling with Landshain is really good. Even with Llama Index, it is good, as compared to Haystack.
PAUL: And a few other free monks.
PAUL: Okay? Now, here, very specifically, again, the expo type, I have defined it as dox underscore chunks, and this is our custom converter.
PAUL: So, within the pipeline, what will be the operations that will be enabled? OCR is false, and do a table structure that I have passed it as true.
PAUL: Alright, now… If…
PAUL: Now, the next part that I'll be talking about is basically the integration with your final rack pipeline.
PAUL: Because once we have done this, so pretty much our discussion with respect to at least one of the major frameworks, toggling is done.
PAUL: Then again, we'll be talking about docklinks only during multi-data, okay? Your multimodal data, when it will come, we'll be talking about that much more.
PAUL: Yes, because the Xbox type is Docklinks. Through Docklinks, we are getting attacked, correct?
PAUL: My default is the hybrid chunker, I think, PL.
PAUL: Alright, now moving to rack pipeline. See, this is a simple pipeline that I have.
PAUL: Okay, now, in this pipeline, if you really look into only one new thing, okay, so some… a few things with respect to Dockling Loader.
PAUL: Okay, export type, that very specifically, then comes Lanch and OpenAI.
PAUL: Chroma, okay, then chains that I have, and then very specifically, filter complex metadata.
PAUL: Okay, so few, implementations. So, I think everybody should be familiar with these imports. Now, I think one new import is there, which is only the export type and docklink, so… which are related to docklings, rather than which are related to, like, language chain, so we have never discussed that.
PAUL: Okay, and then probably an API key check, because this is the point where you need an angle.
PAUL: Because now we are talking about RAD.
PAUL: Before this, there was no requirement of LLM, so don't get confused.
PAUL: Okay, so OpenAI key found, proceeding with the RAT setup.
PAUL: Now, the first thing, using the docklink loader, I'm loading the PDF, the loader.load, then I'm printing, okay? And right now, the export type is doc underscore chunks, so based on that, I'll be getting the chunks.
PAUL: Last time for this document, we got around 41 chunks, so…
PAUL: Here also, I think it will be close to 4… it will be 41 only.
PAUL: 2804069, okay. Just be sure you are passing the exact URL, because 41, as I can see here, document chunks. So really, I don't think that the number of chunks really changes here.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, see, I have the chunks with me. Once the chunks are available, then comes, basically, the embeddings.
PAUL: Okay? So, the first thing I'm, passing what embedding model that I want to use, which is basically our text embedding 3 small. Once we have passed, okay, now, filter document. Now, this is a simple variable, filter complex metadata. Okay,
PAUL: Sometimes we use it, but again, now, this is not that every time you will be using it.
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is that if you are working with complex metadata, because right now the archive document, it was having a lot of metadata, so very specifically for that particular implementation, I've taken into that.
PAUL: Now, this will, basically perform a much more cleaning operation on top of the existing metadata for every chunk that we do maintain.
PAUL: And then finally, I have defined my vector store, so Chroma from documents, then comes your filter documents, embeddings, ChromaDB, and Dockling Demo.
PAUL: Okay, so, alright, so let me just execute this part.
PAUL: Okay, in my local machine, a folder will be created, so vector store created with 41 documents and persisted to .chromaDB.
PAUL: Okay? Because please check imports, don't ask me, like.
PAUL: Importionally, okay? Please figure it out.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, for vision data embedding models, it's different. Yes, I'm sure. So, for vision, if you, very specifically, if I want to create a vision embeddings, models are different, like CLIP models are there, okay, even QVL models are there.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, we are working with text embeddings, guys. We are not working with that.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, building a chain, because yes, I have the vector store. With the vector store, I can create the retriever, okay? So, similarly, LLM initialization, that comes into the picture. After that, a simple prompt template.
PAUL: And then my vector store. So this is pretty much the stuff that you guys have already worked with, nothing, I think, that I need to repeat, okay? And based on that, the RAT chain has been created successfully. Next step, to invoke the chain.
PAUL: Okay, so now, where LLM is being activated, okay? And based on that, I'm getting the information. Okay, so with respect to the answer, this document is a technical report introducing docklink and open source.
PAUL: It highlights the challenges, the document conversion, and all those stuff. So, pretty much, I know that, based on this particular information, it will work pretty much correct. There won't be any type of issues.
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: With respect to, like, you can add more queries, so based on that, I have passed it. So, you can see 3 setup questions, what is docklink, what file format. So, very similar strategy. Within a for loop, I'm invoking the chain 3 times, based on the number of questions that I have.
PAUL: Okay, so previously it was only about 1 question, this time I've just shown you three different questions.
PAUL: what is the use of integrating, LangChain with Docklinks?
PAUL: The idea is that whenever you are working with Lansion, every component can be different. It means that for parsing, you might use a different library. For chunking, you might use a different library. At every point of time, you can change each component. It is not necessary that you will be using everything from LANCH.
PAUL: That's the core part.
PAUL: Because really, with respect to the parsing mechanism, I prefer to use different parses. Dockling is one of my favorites. Unstructured is also a good one, that you can always stick to these two, very similar.
PAUL: For paid-based solutions, then actually for enterprises, Llama Paths is really good.
PAUL: Akhil, can you please explain the RAG pipeline?
PAUL: In the RAT pipeline, what are the things that we have done? So, first of all, we have taken the document. After taking the document, we have read the document, we have converted into chunks. Once the chunks are available, convert it to embedding, pass it to your
PAUL: Vector store, once the vector store is available, create a retriever object, create your final rack chain with the prompt template and the LLM. Once you have passed that, it's pretty much the same retriever initialization to get the stuff, activate the chain, and based on that, we are getting the results.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, see, I think there should not be any question with respect to RAG, because RAG code is exactly just like last time. We have looked into 5 times, 6 times. Last class, 2 times, we have looked into that RAG. Generally, the RAG implementation, I've
PAUL: won't be changing. It will be always fixed.
PAUL: Because that is the main boiler template. Some things might change, because in this part, I'm not using the land chain data loaders. So, very specifically, I'm using the dockling loader.
PAUL: That is the only change, if you really think about it.
PAUL: Other than that, pretty much the rest of the code is pretty same.
PAUL: Aside is just a variant of chain.
PAUL: There are so many different types of chain that you can look into. A symbol chain, staff chain. Okay, so really, that doesn't matter. At the end of the core, part. That is the…
PAUL: Langchain loader, why we are not using. Actually, you can use, I have no restriction, it's totally up to you. I've shown you, okay, the Dockling version. You can use Langchain Data Loaders, I have really no issues in that.
PAUL: And there is different, data extraction for web, versus image versus video, like,
PAUL: Okay, yes, no, like, MegPass or crawling, that… those are different, like, I'm… we are not talking about crawling right now.
PAUL: Krishnapanth, okay, alright, fine. Because the core part is done, now I will move to the next part.
PAUL: There are a few, implementations, I think, with respect to export and serializations, like this part I've already shown you. The idea of using block, and majorly I use exported Markdown formats. On top of Markdown, I apply my chunky.
PAUL: Okay, it's a good practice to do a validation. Similarly, for JSON-based, you can do a export to DIT level. This information is also Word. Export to JSON is also there. So, these are different type of export formats that you can play in Docklets.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: There are runtime errors.
PAUL: Where is runtime errors?
PAUL: Actually, it's up to you. Now, my purpose was to show you Dockling. On top of Docklink, what type of data validation that you apply, you want to do.
PAUL: Adding a data validation staff, that is totally different.
PAUL: Okay? Now, export table to pandas, so this particular option. Okay, now here it's really, like, it's about pandas, lesser about docklings.
PAUL: Okay, it means that if there is a table attribute available within a doc, then you can simply convert it into data frames or CSV. So, this particular option is also available, okay, but it's not docklink doing it.
PAUL: Dockling will tell you, okay, there is a table. Now, if there is a table, then rest of the things are taken care by Panda.
PAUL: Okay? And right now, we know that in our document, there were 3 tables, so based on that, the first 3 tables that we looked into.
PAUL: Okay, now comes batch processing. Now, this part is also… it means that you can pass multiple files in one shot. Batch processing is very, very important, actually, whenever you are working, okay, anywhere in an enterprise level. So, like, generally, my way is, like,
PAUL: I don't use… I use that directory loader. In language engine, there is a concept called a directory looter.
PAUL: Anybody remember?
PAUL: I have talked about that directory loader in LandChain.
PAUL: Okay, if you remember, so generally I look into a directory, then I use different type of glob operation for file selection.
PAUL: And, I keep every batch different based on my file types.
PAUL: It means that PDF files will have a separate batch, DocX a separate batch.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to make your pipelines much cleaner at any point of time. Okay, otherwise, if you feel that if you're working with lesser amount of data, you can pass everything in one shot. There is no restrictions in that, okay? So, right now, the idea is to look for different path, add some validations, check if the path exists or not. If
PAUL: it exists, okay, so we are calling the document converter. Then, based on result, we can say that, okay, the conversion, okay, now you can actually create this particular variable, success, partial, and fate. These three formations are available in your conversion result. If you remember, in Docklink, there is a very separate,
PAUL: The first thing that I told you, if you remember.
PAUL: Okay, somewhere around.
PAUL: You can always get the conversion result from there.
PAUL: Anybody remember the conversion result?
PAUL: Yes, the conversion reason.
PAUL: Okay, so it will always give you the status, errors, everything. So whenever you are working with Docklink, you can actually test it out.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, for each file, what is the main different process? Okay, and on top of that, see, converter.all, so, like, this is the main one, converter.convertAll, you are passing your existing sources, so whatever the existing file that you do have, once the final check has been done, so one by one, the conversion will apply.
PAUL: So, yes, directly this is available.
PAUL: Okay, and always you will be getting this information I told you from the conversion status. Based on that, we're creating an append operation for each of the status, and based on that, you are printing out the final summary of each of the cases.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that this type of implementation, that you should keep it much more in your enterprise-level solutions.
PAUL: Okay, it's not necessary every time during our learning we do it, but sometimes the idea is that you should adapt it much more. Because Langchen, really, like, in Langchen, a lot of things that goes under the hood, that really even I don't know.
PAUL: Okay, now, when you move to specific frameworks, they give you much more low-level control.
PAUL: The idea is always… the focus is towards low-level. If somebody is much more… for backend developers, I feel you should have a low-level power as compared to directly just calling. Exactly, the idea is to manipulate. But directly manipulating landscape, that's not a good practice.
PAUL: So, in that case, we move to some third-party parsing mechanism.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Both are used for different purposes, actually.
PAUL: Now, similarly, like, document enrichment, so this is, like, enable enrichment features, like picture classification, description, this comes much more towards the multimodal side, very specifically. Okay, now, you can… now, what are the new things? Do picture classification through, like, chart, diagrams.
PAUL: Okay, now these things I'll be talking about much more into the multimodal lecture, because during multimodal, these things are much used much more. Do picture description is equal to false, okay, so disable the VLM description, but I feel that this is also an important
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, when you are creating your own document, you cannot keep the images, but you can keep the description of the images. So, generally, we perform, visual tasks like image caption.
PAUL: Okay, so image captioning is one of the major ones, or image descriptors.
PAUL: Through which we replace that image with that piece of text. And finally, that piece of information will be embedded.
PAUL: Okay, so the implementation is pretty much standard. Okay, there is no difference, it's just a few parameters that change with.
PAUL: Okay, and some error handling techniques also that I have kept it for each of, like, when you are converting, if you want to handle very specific type of error, so this is a boilerplate that I have shared with you. If you want, okay, you can implement, or you can implement even better, because right now.
PAUL: Logging and other stuff, I have not kept it, but simple error handling that I have kept. At any point of time, if you feel that success, based on partial, if you're not getting, okay, or if the conversion failed, if the file is corrupt, a lot of checks that can be taken into account. So, few things that I have added in this particular notebook.
PAUL: Is that picture that converts, like, what kind of picture explained in the words? It's not what kind, it will give you a description, picture description.
PAUL: That lonely stuff.
PAUL: Okay, it might say that in that image, there is one dog, one person, flying kite in a green field, something like that. The description will come, and nothing more.
PAUL: Alright guys, so now, the ideas, few things that we have looked into here. Okay, now, this was a core part, because again, like, I know, each framework will take one day. Okay, so, like, tomorrow then we'll be, talking about unstructured
PAUL: It's just, like, similar stuff at the end of the day. Okay, I cannot say that,
PAUL: Really, response, result, I got a key error here, result.
PAUL: import, result, result, result.
PAUL: I take care of…
PAUL: Okay, use the answer, because I feel that it should work, that's why.
PAUL: Because querying the RAG system…
PAUL: Okay, alright, because response, answer, okay, because I can get the answer directly from here also.
PAUL: Okay, just wait.
PAUL: I will add one print statement.
PAUL: Okay, within that, I will take a response…
PAUL: And actually, response. Within that, I need to define the key.
PAUL: Sure.
PAUL: I think that's the only stock that I was looking for.
PAUL: Look at 3 things that I have, let me see.
PAUL: Alright, the core part is done. This part, I will just check with response.
PAUL: And this is the part, because with respect to source document that I have, this particular key.
PAUL: Again, that I feel that. Because source document…
PAUL: This is one time that I have defined here.
PAUL: Because this is the part with respect to… that's why instead of source document, it will be context here. That's why I will just, keep an hash on that one.
PAUL: Because, really, these two lines, as I was updating the lanchan version for this one, okay, so, based on that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: response, and from there, I'll be getting the answer.
PAUL: Alright, let me see, okay…
PAUL: Well, right now, you can start taking questions, basically, with respect to… and tomorrow, we'll be discussing unstructured. And if you are done with unstructured, then probably a little bit of Llama parts.
PAUL: That is the idea.
PAUL: Vivek, how to work with large files, break that files into multiple batches, and based on that, you'll be doing… because in one shot, it's a bad practice to read 10GB or 20GB of data through a single operation.
PAUL: Alright, so let me start, okay, I will just start reading the questions.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take… US people, you can go ahead. Okay, that will be the priority, then I will come to Indian students.
PAUL: There is no difference, both are different frameworks, or something like, just the implementation is different.
PAUL: Athil, if you ask me, Unstructured, it's an enterprise organization, okay? It has a free version of that one. So, Sahil is there, Deva is there, Krishna Kahant is there, okay? So, 3 people.
PAUL: Okay, so one by one, you guys can… so it's totally up to you, it's not necessary, you have to use docklinks. It's just, I'm showing you docklinks. The idea is to explore multiple types of parsing, because at the end of the day, you have to understand, data parsing is one of the most important things. If your parsing technique is bad, you cannot build good RAG. That's why.
deba: Yeah, Paul, can you start, probably?
PAUL: Deva, you can go first, then Krishna, then Sahil, then the list, Rahul, Ramaprakash, Akeem, okay, you come one by one.
deba: Yeah.
deba: Well, sure. So, the question is,
deba: that there could be… once we are looking into the enterprise solution, we could find that there could be a requirement how we have to deal with the embeddings for GBs of data.
deba: For example, there is a use case, actually, for us, where a lot of banking documents, we are converting to the embeddings, and therefore loading to the Cloud SQL vector database in the PostgreSQL, actually, in Google Cloud.
deba: So, the ask is actually, for example, if I go for one
deba: Well, I mean, once they've run.
deba: to do these GBs of data, by doing the chunking and embedding could have been a long process, right? So how the idea from your side, actually, that what… if you're dealing with such scenario, what would be the best solution as for you, actually?
deba: Could I break down the entire data?
PAUL: The size of the data doesn't matter to me.
PAUL: Okay, really, if it is even in petabytes, really doesn't matter. Through pipeline, it will be coming to me in batches.
PAUL: Now, for those batch, part, I need to take care of, like, specifically in that batch, what are the different file types that I'm receiving? Generally, it's a good practice to maintain different pipelines for different type of file format.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on that, like, whatever is your data flow, the core implementation part remains always the same. Now, in your case, with respect to, for example, different banking documents, so let's take something like an ADHAR. In other, you do have text information, but you do also have that image part.
PAUL: Okay, now for those images, again, you have to apply some type of image processing pipeline, you have to extract that particular image that needs to be converted into some type of, I can say, embeddings very specifically, you can do it that way also, and you can save it, or save the original form of the image. That is also a good practice.
PAUL: So, it totally depends upon that.
PAUL: Really, the size of the data doesn't matter to us.
PAUL: Majorly, like, the data engineering team, or someone who will figure it out for you.
deba: Okay.
PAUL: Because the ETL pipeline building part is not your part.
deba: That's good, that's good.
deba: Understood, because I come from the data engineering background only, so I understand this.
deba: One more question, maybe, that is, for example, if it is a daily basis, if you have to do the embeddings, and there could be some common
deba: biddings, right? And we are passing the hyperparameter, like, how much percentage of, maybe the, what is it called? The common embeddings, right? The common.
PAUL: Common embeddings means… CC, common impedance, what is the meaning of that?
deba: I mean to say, like, for example, if you have to parse a document which has been… or a file which has been parsed yesterday, and I have to again parse it today, having some additional data into it.
PAUL: So, for that document file version system, so which will tell you that, okay, in this document, these many lines that got updated. Then, based on that particular logic, you will be adding those type of lines as a new chunk.
PAUL: That is one option. One option is by using the metadata, delete the entire, old document and the new document version that you have uploaded in your VectorDB. Multiple approaches are there.
PAUL: Their AI doesn't count. This is pure software development.
deba: That means… that means the metadata has to be regenerated out of the file, and the older metadata has to be compared, and the newer one has to be extracted in.
PAUL: Yes, you can always do the comparison, because generally, what is there in the chunk, I keep it in the metadata only.
PAUL: It actually helps me to apply any type of filtration technique.
PAUL: Okay.
deba: So much both. Thank you. Yeah, please, please.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Next, I can think Sahil is there, Krishna Kanth is there, you guys can go ahead, Rahul Parihar, Arkhail, Rama Krishna.
PAUL: PA is asking his response time for Doppling is more, it depends, like, what type of… if you're going with VLM, for sure it will be towards the higher side.
PAUL: Okay, if you are using just pure docklings, then it won't be such a difference.
PAUL: Yes, Krishna Kant.
krishna kanth: I'm trying to… Paul, the quick question is, we seem to have been.
PAUL: Be louder, be louder. Like, the audio is very low.
krishna kanth: Paul, are you able to hear me?
PAUL: Yes, better now.
krishna kanth: Yeah, take it. So, I would just want to see, I'm trying to,
krishna kanth: scan a embedded PDF, so when… or a scanned PDF, right? Which has the content, but it's… it's like a image for each page, right? So now I have to extract the image, and inside the text of it, and the image also has tables.
krishna kanth: text, and again, images with text. So we have this complex, format of, and different layouts as well, right? So…
krishna kanth: I see that you have shown us today some nice things, but does dock pulling directly can help us here.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no.
krishna kanth: No problem.
PAUL: Dockling Direct, you need to work with a very specific type of, like, one example I showed you, layout parser. Through layout parser, you have to understand the document.
PAUL: How it is there.
PAUL: What are the things? Because if a table is there within an image.
PAUL: Okay, it becomes really a problem.
PAUL: Okay, now, generally, it's not a problem, it means that you have to take multiple steps for that. So, probably for that, where is that exact table coordinate? You can crop it out, or you can actually use the bounding box coordinates, and then on top of that, you have to look for a table extraction algorithms.
PAUL: It's meant a two-step. First of all, you have to always analyze what type of document, what is…
PAUL: There, header, footer, how that structure has been defined.
krishna kanth: So, is there any pipeline that helps us, like, Vince, is there any…
PAUL: There is no direct pipeline. Nobody else builds a single short library to do that.
krishna kanth: You have to combine multiple libraries, and you have to build a solution in that way.
krishna kanth: Fuck.
krishna kanth: Okay.
PAUL: Because really, like, if you ask LLMs directly, okay, how many images are there.
PAUL: Okay, sometimes I feel it says correct, and sometimes I feel it says wrong. Or even I cannot trust the LLMs every time.
krishna kanth: The problem is the… I directly uploaded this PDF that I'm working on into ChatGPT, and it was not able to do that. But whereas Gemini was able to do that.
krishna kanth: Okay.
PAUL: It totally depends, like, that's why I'm telling you, I cannot trust LLMs for these type of tasks.
krishna kanth: Yeah.
PAUL: Because the data cleaning part, the data parsing part, everything that you need to take care of. If you feel at any point of time that you are not getting the exact information which is available with your document, it means that you need to mark… work much more towards the layout side parsing site.
krishna kanth: So, and also, obviously, like, to remove the noise as well, like, let's say if the brightness of the PDF is low, or, like, increase the grayscale, everything you need to…
PAUL: things with classical visions, you can actually do that. So, for example, every PDF pitch can be converted into an image. Later on, on top of those images, you can apply basic
PAUL: vision-based algorithms. Okay, like, simply, like I told you. Generally, I perform binarization, OS tools, binarization, yeah, those type of tasks. Very specifically, if it's for handwritten type of tasks, then on top of that, I apply OCR.
PAUL: Nobody applies OCR directly. There are certain image techniques that you do. Apply, then you have to apply OCR.
krishna kanth: The swimmer. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, next.
Ramprakash: Paul, Grandpa here.
PAUL: ramped up again.
Ramprakash: Yeah. Paul, actually, you see, I'm unable to locate that, today discussion files, whatever that Python files and, Jupyter files. Can you reshare it, the right path, GitHub?
PAUL: Do you have access to Notion?
Ramprakash: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, open notion.
PAUL: go to today's date. It's pretty much standard. Everybody has got the fines.
Ramprakash: So yeah, I'm looking at, GitHub, whatever you…
PAUL: GitHub notion, I am telling.
PAUL: You open your notion.
PAUL: Notions are… Notion is there for this particular course that I have already shared. Go to that specific lecture, the sixth lecture.
Ramprakash: Factors.
PAUL: Here, you will be happy.
Ramprakash: Okay, thank you.
PAUL: GitHub will change based on the module, always remember that. But this part is always fixed. So, bookmark Notion.
Ramprakash: Thank you.
PAUL: Good.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, my, my question is a little longer. You know, what I'm trying to understand is…
Rahul Parihar: Steve, in terms of this class structure, I'm just appreciated, but my understanding is…
Rahul Parihar: In the Curie translation is the first step where different techniques that I'm… I try evaluating, like multi-curie, rack fusion, decomposition, setback, and height, you know? So, say, suppose setback made my, way.
Rahul Parihar: What I'm trying to get is, when I'm… when I got the proper cushion.
Rahul Parihar: I'm trying to route… use the routing to do…
Rahul Parihar: logical routing versus semantic routing. Why semantic? Because based on that question, I wanted to route it to the… I will not just have a vector store, I will, in real time in production system, I will have relational DB, I may have graph DB, and that's where I have to, you know, do it.
Rahul Parihar: My question is, two, set. One is the… one is the process, end-to-end process that connects
Rahul Parihar: And then, second is, like, if I'm trying to step back and decide that, based on my evaluation technique, you said,
Rahul Parihar: the generation, you know, and retrieval evaluation, techniques. So, I'm using eval, the eval… the LLM evaluation framework, like Deep Eval, you know?
Rahul Parihar: And I'm trying to understand that whichever question gives me a proper evaluation results.
Rahul Parihar: That question is supposed… is the first test for me to consider.
Rahul Parihar: But you had a different view, saying that you need to have a context recall. I'm just talking about evaluation. You had a context recall.
Rahul Parihar: I'm saying context recall and context precision is dependent on expected output, but I don't have an output, so I will only go with.
PAUL: See, what is your requirement? It means that somebody asked the query.
PAUL: leave the retrieval, leave the generation part, okay? Now, what's the first step that you are referring? It means that.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, my question, my query translation should be proper, right? Unless and until I don't ask the right question whether to rag or to LLM. I'm not going to get there.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
Rahul Parihar: Agile.
PAUL: Alright, now, with respect to question, fine, like, you were performing some type of translation task. Okay, now query transformation that you were doing.
PAUL: The idea is that if somebody has not written an interrogative sentence, they have simply written words, the idea is to convert it into an interrogative sentence, and so that the retriever gets a better context with respect to that.
Rahul Parihar: Correct. But what are my challenges? Based on that question, I wanted to semantically route that question to the right data source.
Rahul Parihar: That's a problem, right?
Rahul Parihar: Like, the kitchen should have the trigger, how to solve that problem?
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, good example.
PAUL: Really, it depends upon how you are building the solution. I generally use intent-based dictionaries. Okay, so now let's take the example here, just wait.
Rahul Parihar: You got the cushion, right, where I'm coming from?
PAUL: I got somehow, it means that you have multiple sources and you want to redirect it to some source, okay? So, for example.
PAUL: Like, caution is there.
PAUL: Okay, now, for example… Nothing.
Rahul Parihar: and…
PAUL: So, like, if I do something like this, how to land?
PAUL: how to learn Langshan.
PAUL: Okay, a simple query, or probably, like, if anything, learn Langshuin, that has been converted into some type of, I can see, a transformed query, T query for now. Now, your job is basically from this query to…
PAUL: Redirected, so probably you might have multiple sources.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, do you want…
PAUL: is…
Rahul Parihar: Do you want a document? Do you want a video? Do you want an image, you know, or what are the user looking for? You know, that question could be anything.
PAUL: That cushion would be there.
Rahul Parihar: hunt.
PAUL: Si, see.
PAUL: you cannot directly say that from this particular query. Then, based on this query, you have to generate another query exactly. It means that.
PAUL: generally the concept of comes. It means that he wants a much more deep-dive explanation of this particular question. It means that, generally, what I do, I can apply something like a COT, a chain of thoughts, on top of this.
PAUL: So that it becomes much more comprehensive.
PAUL: Okay, before sending it, okay, for retrieval. And generally, like, in chain of thoughts, I can ask, do you want this particular topic, this particular topic, this particular topic?
PAUL: Okay, now, probably, on top of that, the query will become in background, the query will become bigger. Now, on top of that, query decomposition, and then comes your retrieval task.
PAUL: Or probably, sometimes to do optimization, I can create an intent bit system, where there are multiple entities, and through entities, for example, I can define Landshine as an entity, okay? And that particular entity is something like, through that entity, I can actually match a metadata, and I can give the results in a faster way.
PAUL: So, it totally depends, like, how you are doing that solution. I told you.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, so we've… we're trying to… so I'm trying to adopt AdaptiveRack to turn the retrieval and the generation into a self-reflective state machine using LendGraph, okay? As simple as that. But I'm not able to reach there. The reason I'm not able to reach there is because
Rahul Parihar: Because of various factors, you know.
Rahul Parihar: and I can send you an email on that, but what I'm trying to say is, if there are my different nodes and ages are connected, and whenever there is a corrective query that is coming, which is… which is… and when the grounding is failing below the threshold.
Rahul Parihar: it tries to say that, okay, I have to improve the faithfulness by 12 points, or reduce hallucination, or cut the token caused by this much points, you know?
Rahul Parihar: See, based on this understanding of basic POC mechanism, this…
Rahul Parihar: Obviously, the structure of the course is good, but when we are trying to build a productionalized RAS, there are various challenges, as you can imagine, right? So what I'm trying to connect to is.
Rahul Parihar: an end-to-end flow, where I have six phases. One is query translation, second is routing, third is evaluation, fourth is security and guardrails, fifth is chunking, and sixth is scalability with adaptiveness, adaptive rack. Now.
PAUL: Probably the thing that you are looking for, it will be, like, probably in the 4th or the 5th month.
Rahul Parihar: weather…
PAUL: Nothing.
Rahul Parihar: Whether the parsing fit into this, you know, is what I'm trying to understand.
PAUL: parsing at any point of time. The first phase in data ingestion is parsing.
PAUL: I cannot understand that till the first part.
PAUL: It can be docklinked, it can be unstructured, it can be any library.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, it will… okay. So…
PAUL: The first phase is data ingestion. The idea is to show you multiple parsing frameworks. That's the only part. I'm not talking nothing about tracking it.
PAUL: without proper, that's the main thing, like, if you don't have high-quality data, it really doesn't matter. You apply re-ranking, you apply fusion, really doesn't work.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, yeah, I understand parsing… parsing by default will be, comprehended, but, you know, I can live without… without having a dockling parser, you know, this is what I'm saying.
PAUL: Yes. So again, like, tomorrow we'll be talking about unstructured. It is not necessary. Somebody might use completely Llama parts. It's totally up to somebody. My idea is to tell you, okay, these are the open source solutions, these are some paid solutions. Now, it's totally up to you what you want to use.
PAUL: That's the idea of keeping the module. I cannot say only one thing. By default, I have taught you language and loaders, nothing I will teach other than that.
PAUL: Because in production, actually, we use docklings, we use unstructured.
Rahul Parihar: See, we have, what I'm trying to get to out of this course is connect all the dots and get a better understanding of a POC.
PAUL: all the dots, it will come at the end, not right now.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but, you know, till now, I have… what I… what I'm trying to say is, for example, just query translation. We just talked about decomposition, but what about…
PAUL: These things will come after 2 months or 3 months when I'll be talking about. Nothing I have taught anything. You ask… you are asking questions very specific to your problem. But till now, we have not reached that level in the class only. Few people might not ask, like, get your question also, who are just beginners.
PAUL: You have to understand, see, we will raise, step by step, in one shot, I cannot teach you everything.
PAUL: Never.
Rahul Parihar: I understand where you're coming from, but yeah, okay.
Rahul Parihar: So, for example… okay, got it.
PAUL: That's why, like, your query, I have always told you to drop a mail, but you have never dropped me a mail.
Rahul Parihar: I have dropped it, bounced back, can you…
PAUL: How it can bounce back, other people are sending now, telling bounce back.
Rahul Parihar: I have sent… let me… drop me an email address again.
PAUL: Because your problems are much more towards your niche side, and really, with respect to production, when you ask a few things, I can only tell you the strategy. This is how I have worked in some use cases. Based on that, you can take that decision.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, because really, like, making sets and generally, like, a lot of things are there which I have not told you also. With respect to when you are creating the embeddings, do you create questions, like a question-answer form in that Varang works better? A lot of things are there.
Rahul Parihar: Is the email address there on the Notion? Notion site?
PAUL: app at the rate… I don't think it is there, but, it's…
Rahul Parihar: We added to the notion?
PAUL: Notion, I can add it, just wait.
Rahul Parihar: I'll send you my queries, you know, what I'm trying to talk to.
PAUL: Okay, in the top part, in the email part, I have added… App at the rate, questioning.
PAUL: On the landing page, I have added it.
Rahul Parihar: Yep.
PAUL: Please try to do a hard refresh. Based on that, you will get it. Alright, fine. Next.
PAUL: Next, next, next, next, please go ahead, anyone.
PAUL: Tahil, Sanjay Sagur, okay?
akhil: Yeah, I have all, Akel this side. So, can you please explain, where you have connected the, you know, the line chain, framework in this document, parsing?
PAUL: Whatever you will see in the import, there is a language and docklink import is there. There, I have connected.
akhil: So, you have imported, and then you have used the document.
PAUL: Langchen Dockling Package, correct.
akhil: pictures.
PAUL: Okay, just do a controller, based on that, you will get the inputs. Yes, next.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Deepanjan Majumdar: I just wanted to understand, I didn't basically go through the earlier videos because I joined…
PAUL: It is not required, see, really. Like, earlier videos really doesn't matter to us. This class, this class is totally different. The idea is to read different type of file formats using a specific framework. That's the only thing.
Deepanjan Majumdar: The question that I had might be out of context, but you can just, maybe, naj or say that, I mean, we have already covered.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, go ahead, go ahead, please.
Deepanjan Majumdar: The thing is that, when we have… let's say we have already a rag for… we have a document which contains both, you know, text as well as, images, right?
PAUL: Cheers.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Texts are basically correlative to the images. Now, let's say we have already created a rag out of the, those documents, where we have different, maybe, separate image and a textual, rag.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Right? And now, when a user query comes in, I'm just, curious to understand that, the query should basically resort to,
Deepanjan Majumdar: an image and the text, which are both, you know, closely correlated. Let's say, for example, I have an AWS document where
Deepanjan Majumdar: there is some architectural diagram that is being defined as a diagram, and then image, and then textual description explaining that particular diagram, right?
Deepanjan Majumdar: Querying, when I, as a user, query to the agent, right?
Deepanjan Majumdar: How… I mean, have you already covered this, that how would it basically, you know, return,
PAUL: Multimodal, nothing I have covered.
PAUL: It will be probably after, I think, in future modules, like, after 8, I think, at least.
Deepanjan Majumdar: This is also going to be covered in that, like, correlated, text and image,
PAUL: I'll be taking, exactly, see, the idea is that at any point of time, whether you have an image, my idea is basically to convert that image into some type of image description.
PAUL: If it is a… see, there are multiple ways. I can say one image to description.
PAUL: one image to HTML. Okay, and probably, if I have an image, if you have workflows, generally, if you work with workflows, generally, I can convert it into a mermaid format. Okay, and then probably through Mermaid, that I can create a Markdown. Markdown can, like, Mermaid can be rendered in Markdown.
PAUL: In that way, I will try to build it. But for that, again, a very specific another LLM that I will be using it.
PAUL: Because every LLM doesn't have a multimodal support. To create that image captioning or image description, I do need an ML.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Okay, so basically, and then you'll… after you caption or convert the image into text, you're going to map the exact text chunks, from the…
Deepanjan Majumdar: the text drag, and then you'll return both, right? That's what you mean.
PAUL: Yes, that's the idea.
PAUL: That comes in multimodal drag.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Okay.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Thank you.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Next.
Sanjay Sagore: Anybody can go, I've unmuted a lot of people.
Sanjay Sagore: Hello, Paul. Sanjay's here.
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, Paul, earlier I was discussed, no, regarding one project that…
Sanjay Sagore: getting correct procedure that I have in my folder. So, can I share my screen here a bit, if you can take your time? It will not take much longer time.
PAUL: Okay, I've added you to panelists. Next, I think Roeth is there, Mudassar is there, anyone can go with?
PAUL: Hey, Paul, I need to share my screen. Alright, I will add you to panelist.
Rohit Srivastava: bees.
PAUL: Madassav…
Mudassar Hakim: Hey, Paul. So, Paul, I think my struggles are a little, maybe, different here. I kind of get into installation issues, and I'm kind of trying to get them done, and I'm lagging behind in the understanding part, and mostly I'm just chat GPTing most of the time. Is there a way…
PAUL: Yeah.
Mudassar Hakim: It's not…
PAUL: part where you are facing, like, which package is created?
Mudassar Hakim: It's not just one of a piece, a line chain sometimes. But again, I think the… I mean, I understand TA is not a feasibility as of now, but can we at least have this code given before… a few days before, so that I can at least run it once and see if there is something I need to look into prior to the session?
Mudassar Hakim: Because if I get…
PAUL: Should I shake its flag to the session.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, because if the installations are done right, I can have more focused discussion on what is going on, explore and ask my questions there. Now, my 50% of time has simply gone into figuring out why this is not working, fix this part, fix that part, and I could not really get most of the session out.
Mudassar Hakim: I did a… which I should have done. And ultimately, I'm just trying to…
PAUL: CCC, first of all.
Mudassar Hakim: Like…
PAUL: why it is not working, share your screen and tell me, okay? Let's…
Mudassar Hakim: People are like, you know, do that in the beginning, right? In the beginning, there are tons of.
PAUL: I got your point, but at least, like, that's the approach.
Mudassar Hakim: point where you can select me and say, okay, so now share your screen. This happens after the end of the session. Right now, we are looking into it. So, I understand those challenges, and the solution which I am trying to call out here is, can we have this code share a few days before?
PAUL: Really, I cannot guarantee. It totally depends upon my schedule. For example, like, I know that at least before 1 hour, I can… I generally do a push, or sometimes it can be 10 minutes before also.
PAUL: Because, see, I can share a draft version, but I can get dropped version if I'm not working with.
PAUL: Okay, that… rather than, that's the main stuff, because do you want me to create a specific file only to check that whether your imports are working or not?
PAUL: That I can probably do.
Mudassar Hakim: Something in that direction. I mean, I get the implementation might be… sorry, something we, you know.
PAUL: I got your point, I got your point. Just because he was stuck in installation, you cannot execute any other stuff. That's the pinpoint.
Mudassar Hakim: Because I feel like I want to run the code along with the class, and so that I can see and I can do things.
PAUL: It's a blame me.
Mudassar Hakim: that's where I'm, you know, being very much.
PAUL: If the content is ready, then only I can provide it. That's the main part. If it is not ready, okay, like, then probably I cannot do it.
PAUL: That's the main thing. It's not like that everything is frozen in one chart. I have to also check few…
Mudassar Hakim: You could have a, you know, a watermark checkpoint somewhere, maybe by the day before yesterday evening, like.
PAUL: See, now see, you are telling, that who will do? I have to do. If I am not available, then who will do? That's the question comes. So, committing before telling, it's a very hard stuff. You have to understand, if I tell you now, and if I don't do it till the next.
Rohit Srivastava: doing food.
PAUL: That's the main problem. Okay.
Rohit Srivastava: What the hex?
PAUL: But I got your point, it happens not only with you, there can be a lot of students, but the idea is that going forward, this installation issue, somehow you need to resolve it. It should not take maximum, I can say, for any type, it takes 5 minutes to 10 minutes.
Mudassar Hakim: I get it.
PAUL: that's like…
Mudassar Hakim: My case could be one-off, but the point is that if the import parts can be sorted before the session, maybe one Archalo, I mean, I get up.
PAUL: So I import, but I can share it. It means that same.
Mudassar Hakim: quickly go through it before the session, because roughly 15, 20, 30 minutes goes into that. I feel like if I get that before, before starting of the class, I can delicately sit and sort it out.
PAUL: I can agree to your point, I caught your point.
Mudassar Hakim: Imports, really, I've not used any new imports, only the Dockling games. Langchen imports are pretty much the same one.
PAUL: So, you might have an issue with respect to docklinks only.
Mudassar Hakim: Or something else, I'm not sure.
PAUL: There is nothing wrong… see, the process is exactly the same what others are doing. Others are able to do it. So the idea is, I only told you, like, based on your system, just remove all the versions and do the installation. That is the easiest way of doing it.
PAUL: Using version-specific stuff can be a problem. But in your case, what is the major package which is creating the problem that you feel?
Mudassar Hakim: I mean, before, when I was doing it, something went wrong with the docklink package, then I sorted that out…
PAUL: Like, what is wrong? Generally, see, in Docklings, generally, there is nothing that wrong happens. That's why, really, I want to understand from your error, like, what error that you got. Because, see, when you share your errors, the others might be facing that similar issue.
Mudassar Hakim: That's the thing, Nepal. By the time I'm sharing, it's end of the session. It's not something I get a chance to do it in the beginning of the session. It could be something very trivial from your perspective. I'm not denying that. But the point is, for me, it's a blocker.
Mudassar Hakim: And that's why I'm trying to figure out a way how we can solve this. And all I'm asking is that, fine, your circumstances are very different. Maybe a day before is not possible, maybe an hour before, at least somewhere you can give some code before, so that I'm not…
PAUL: Generally, I run it, if you look into GitHub, 10 minutes, 15 minutes, it can be 30 minutes, I generally push it before the class only hours.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay, if you can just put it on the chat message, maybe, once it's ready.
PAUL: if things are well, maybe a little prior, so that you can, you know, just put it there. And you can put a comment also. I'm not saying that that should be the final frozen…
Mudassar Hakim: version, right? You can say that, hey, there are ongoing commits happening on that. It's perfectly okay, understandable. But at least the major…
PAUL: What happens?
Mudassar Hakim: imported, na.
PAUL: previously in other batches, once I have done it, and there was a pain point.
PAUL: Like, whenever I create content, I add more content, okay? Now, once I check that part, okay, now, if somebody later on checks and see that, okay, his content has been… now, they ask, why you have removed this, why…
Mudassar Hakim: It doesn't matter.
PAUL: That's the main goal.
Mudassar Hakim: I have the liberty in saying that it's an in-progress document. It is a risk that the candidate or the student is taking, right? And I'm willing to take that.
PAUL: closed.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm okay, perfectly, the entire thing changes from A to Z. I'm perfectly okay.
PAUL: That's the thing, I don't think…
Mudassar Hakim: fix it, probably.
Mudassar Hakim: format or get things sorted before.
PAUL: I got your point, see, your point is valid, but again, I cannot take it one, because, like, I know you can be good, but there are other students also. Once he or she, if even she looks into the draft. So, probably, that's the only thing. I will keep an import part as a separate notebook, only so that you can check.
PAUL: Alright, at every GitHub, I will add that import.ipynb file in the notebook.
Mudassar Hakim: just scrutinize and streamline that part now, I mean, my 80% of challenges are gone. I think I'm struggling that, at least for me. I might not be echoing the thoughts of others here, but I think I'm
Mudassar Hakim: I'm struggling here. If that gets started, I can have a very comfortable.
PAUL: Understanding of things here. I got your point, I got your point, you don't need to repeat that, I got… but the idea is that you should be able to resolve it within 5 minutes, so again, you need to work on that.
Mudassar Hakim: I'm completely on the same page, but I hope maybe after the sessions, I would be improved, yeah? Charlotte, I don't want to take much time now. Thanks, Paul.
PAUL: Alright, fine, I got your point. So I will just create a new notebook by the name import.ip. So that at least you can have a check on that, okay?
Mudassar Hakim: so I'm also. Thanks.
PAUL: Hmm.
Rohit Srivastava: Hey, Sarancho? Yeah, my, my issue got resolved. Sir, thank you. There was some.
PAUL: How is it delivered?
Rohit Srivastava: No, it was a trivial. It was a trivial, right.
PAUL: So, thank you, thank you so much.
PAUL: funded?
Sanjay Sagore: Yeah, useful, thank you. Let's hear in my screen.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: You are in panelists, others, admin is there.
PAUL: Okay, and then… Devai and Akil already I've taken, so I will just lower your hand.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: Okay.
Sanjay Sagore: Is it visible?
PAUL: Yes, yes, it is available.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, so this is the project. Here, I have these queries in this folder, SQLDB queries.
Sanjay Sagore: These are the snowflake queries.
PAUL: All right.
Sanjay Sagore: So, this is the… these are the long queries.
Sanjay Sagore: Basically, it shows the users and cost of the resources of AWS.
Sanjay Sagore: So, there are a number of queries here.
Sanjay Sagore: So, average storage spend, something like that. Monthly storage cost, like that only, so…
Sanjay Sagore: These are the categories of this particular queries we have. These are basically reports only.
Sanjay Sagore: So… Right now, we have the portal.
Sanjay Sagore: to get this report based on these queries. So, we have the portal through the menu, like dashboard, and if I select the
Sanjay Sagore: dollar use menu, then I will get report of this, built on executing this particular procedure.
Sanjay Sagore: Now, just to… what I'm doing now, I'm just adding one feature where, just the user can put, non-technical person, user can only put the text like that, please send the report for the, dashboard, actual dollar used.
Sanjay Sagore: And that particular report should be displayed on his, whatever the chat or something like that, and the graph will be displayed to him.
Sanjay Sagore: So, just for that only, I have doubt that whether should I embed all those particular store procedures, or just should I create only… right now, I have loaded this particular
Sanjay Sagore: Store project.
Sanjay Sagore: N?
PAUL: So, actually, you were loading your entire…
PAUL: The queries… okay, table's not there. Those are mainly queries that you have, no.
Sanjay Sagore: Mmm.
PAUL: Okay, for your query generation part…
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, so just query means I will just put the text, and I will get the, based on the text, I need that particular query so that I can execute and provide the report to him.
PAUL: CCC, right now you have the queries, okay? Now, where you have the setup questions, it means that if a simple user asks.
PAUL: This query will be mapped to this. Now, how you are doing that?
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, that's what, means, whether should I embed all those queries and questions, and then…
PAUL: At least the queries, because queries are important, because, see, directly, we don't know, so at least, like, in query level, at least in these type of cases, I prefer to add at least some type of
PAUL: It not needs to be a query, but at least a comprehensive. For example, like this particular, query, okay, does this, at least in detail. Then try to add it.
Sanjay Sagore: Question and answer, suppose one… for one query, I can have set up 10 questions, like.
Sanjay Sagore: It can… a user can put anything.
PAUL: Generally, like, 10, you don't need at least 4 examples For each particular query?
PAUL: Oh, so do I need to embed these queries also, or just, you know, just the metadata, and here only I have to embed that one? That is the process. Queries are important, because at the end of the day, people will be asking query. Okay, so that's why to do that particular matching query will be important.
PAUL: And how comprehensive is your query? That is also important.
Sanjay Sagore: I think if I'm matching with the query, that will not be vulnerable, because, see, this is the long one. So, whether should I embed only the question and answer only, or how… whether processor also needed?
Sanjay Sagore: See, bye.
PAUL: Again, like, really directly sending the query
PAUL: Because if I do a query intent matching, direct operation.
PAUL: The idea is that, do you want to send all your queries, like, to the LLM?
PAUL: Because, again, now your chunking will matter based on every query, like, whichever parameter that you have given. Like, each query will become a chunk.
PAUL: Correct? Correct. Now, for that, each query when you have… so, in the metadata, can there be some type of question that this particular query is related to this?
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: comprehensive discussion.
Sanjay Sagore: See, I can… I have the questions that are in metadata on the question, category also, description.
PAUL: Okay, so this is manually, see, right now in the portions, so this is Langchain team. This is a simple, very… not even a piece of text, which will be added to every metadata of your every document.
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, right.
PAUL: to Langshin team really, like,
PAUL: I want this to be much more comprehensive.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because, see, my idea is simple. If I have a SQL query. Now, the idea is that, what is that query doing, in simple terms?
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, using that information, I can create filters at a later point. If you don't want in your main document also, you can keep it.
PAUL: Like, before, your main chunk, okay, it means that you have the big query on top of that, at least two to three lines, I can say, a definition or a comprehensive, like, what exactly this query is doing.
Sanjay Sagore: What is doing? Okay.
PAUL: Based on that, the search, because, see, nobody will write the query.
PAUL: If you directly use only queries, it becomes very hard.
PAUL: Really, to match.
PAUL: at the relationship, so always describe that particular query that is doing. It becomes much easier for any embedding model to search on top of that text.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, so like this only, I mean, top of that, I will just write that, whatever the…
PAUL: Yeah, and apply your, chunking in such a way that you have that divider. That, okay, now this query ends, this is another query. So you define a structure that, okay, first thing that will come is basically a query explanation or something like that. One tag you have, then comes your actual query.
PAUL: In that trite to make a structure.
PAUL: Then create the document.
PAUL: For a junkie.
PAUL: This is a strategy, because directly I don't feel you. If you directly pass, it will really work so good. Because at the end of the day, it needs some type of description or text to understand the need.
PAUL: Please share the link to the Google Sheet. Hasan, I don't have any Google Sheet.
Mudassar Hakim: Paul, I remember sometime back you had given a library or some GitHub report that does this stuff, exactly, right? You give the free text and it converts it to query?
PAUL: This is VANA.ai.
Mudassar Hakim: Vana, right, right. So, would that help here?
PAUL: Yeah, but he is a custom pipeline. In this custom pipeline, it's better to use in that way.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, God.
PAUL: He will help you, but again, his solution, he completely needs to switch to one.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, there's.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, thanks, actually, current grid or not.
PAUL: the idea is, I hope you get it, because to map the query, you need a proper query description. If you don't have a query description, it always becomes a problem.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, generally, that's why in any type of coding patterns I'm telling, I always try to give doc strings, detailed doc strings.
Sanjay Sagore: Higher than open.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, what that function is doing, okay, that dock string will tell you, if you actually don't add dog strings, it becomes problem for the AI.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because if it is a normal programming language, like Pandas and others, it can understand. But if you're building your own custom framework, so exactly what it is doing, it becomes hard. So, the idea is to use better talk strength. So, similarly, the idea is explanation.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, so one thing I got that, I just, I will embed that, in each queries, I will add the query description. So, again, here in metadata, do I need questions, or also questions, setup questions in metadata?
PAUL: In metadata, like, do you have different types of categories, as you told?
PAUL: One is shit. So, keep that at least, like, you… I can see your dashboard query is there already. So, this looks good to me.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, because if…
PAUL: the queries are related to dashboard directly, you can search by using that particular filter.
Sanjay Sagore: Right. And any, any setup questions do I need to put here also, like that, how…
PAUL: You don't need to ask right here. If you see two things, question, okay, or an explanation, whichever you feel that.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, fine, thanks.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, let me complete that, and if we can just guide on that. I will complete and run that.
PAUL: Alright, fine. All right, all right.
PAUL: Okay, next.
PAUL: People reassign. Admin is there, admin, admin, please go ahead.
PAUL: Akel is, Akel already done, please.
akhil: Yeah.
PAUL: No, right now, Akhil, we are not going through that strategies.
akhil: So we will cover it next year.
PAUL: Yes, it will come in future. First, right now, everything that we are doing is neighbor, I hope you understand.
akhil: Okay. Actually, I joined… okay.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Related mainly, right now, in the initial two weeks, I think once I start with the project, the idea is that little bit idea, few people might not be familiar with Fast API, so the exact rack that we have.
PAUL: N7 notebook. I will just take that rack, and I will just try to make an application out of that and deploy it.
PAUL: So that you guys at least be familiar with some level of ops.
PAUL: That's the strategy.
akhil: Hit.
PAUL: Okay, alright, Akel… done admin.
PAUL: Admin and the Panjan, I think, again, you have raised. So, admin on the Panjan, anybody can go ahead.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Hey, Paul, sorry. Just another question, just a brief one.
Deepanjan Majumdar: So, let's say I want to, you know, I have very domain-specific,
Deepanjan Majumdar: websites, or in my organization, I've got, you know, a lot of different, pages, web pages, where we have added our own documentation for our own domain, right? Now, those domain has got business processes, right? They do stuff to, you know.
Deepanjan Majumdar: achieve some functionality in our business. So now my, thing is that, let's say I convert all of them into rag, and now I want to generate, you know, kind of workflows out of those racks through agent, through some agent.
Deepanjan Majumdar: So what do you think, I mean, is it… is general RAG going to help, or we'll have to do something like a graph rag, or knowledge… a knowledge base kind of a RAG to…
Deepanjan Majumdar: achieve.
PAUL: The idea is that the information that you are looking for is embedded within those, I guess, some type of documentations which are available.
PAUL: Yeah. And based on that, what is the final thing that you want to do? It means that you want to extract some information, and based on that, what is the final task goal?
Deepanjan Majumdar: I'll tell you. Let's say, let's say, let's take identity and access management, right?
Deepanjan Majumdar: So, we have got IDPs, like, for example, Okta or KeyClow, whatever, right? They have their own documentation, right?
PAUL: No, I don't have any workflow.
Deepanjan Majumdar: They have admin APIs, which tells that what all things you can do, what all APIs we have support for, with which you can configure our system. Like, for example, with which you can configure Okta, let's say, for a user.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Now, I want to basically, you know, take that entire documentation, I'll scrape and create a rag out of it.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Now, that documentation is available to my agent, let's say. Now, I want my agent, you know, to read those documentation, and
Deepanjan Majumdar: create workflows
Deepanjan Majumdar: which will help provision, the IDEP, IDP, which is basically, let's say, for a user. So that's the use case.
PAUL: Yes, see, see, really, like, agent parts leave it. Your code, your main idea, so if I'm taking it, you have the documentation, the idea is, like, how to do the setup.
PAUL: In simple terms. Okay, now that particular how to do the setup, if you feel that, like, through web scraping or through some documentation, if you can bring that data, okay, and you can put it in VectorDB, so you can attach a retriever and you can do the major task.
Deepanjan Majumdar: My problem is that generating the workflow from that documentation. Is it possible through general, simple drive?
Deepanjan Majumdar: Or do I have…
PAUL: Generating the workflow. Now, see, in the document, is there some type of image, figure, flow? Now, based on what you will be doing, if you have only text, nothing, it means that even if you pass a very long shot of text.
PAUL: to the LLM, to understand. Okay, again, I don't feel, because I think within a documentation, there will be multiple types of setups, like, as you told.
PAUL: So, directly workflow definition, it cannot be done. At least, I think that if you feel that, say, if you feel that, okay, now this is a workflow, at least provide some examples.
PAUL: I prefer always providing some examples, that, okay, now, this is a something. That's the idea of using templates, or prompts. Through prompt, you tell that, okay, now, this is how I want my output to be manipulated, or in this particular structure.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Like, multi-shot prompts.
PAUL: prompt is one, and the another is data level also, because at the end of the day, the actual information will come. But they are trying to keep, for example, in your documentation.
PAUL: Okay, if flows are missing for that particular setup, by yourself, create a flow through Mermaid or through Markdown, okay, and you can append it.
PAUL: Basically, as a single chunk. Really doesn't matter with the rest of the document, just add it on the top.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Okay.
Deepanjan Majumdar: So what I…
PAUL: That way, at least it will know the flow, because you will have a fixed flow for every user will be… if the flow is fixed.
PAUL: keep that. Otherwise, if the flow changes with respect to time, you have to keep multiple examples.
Deepanjan Majumdar: We'll have to add those, flows explicitly.
PAUL: Yes, it's something like, now, when I'm talking about flows, so what do you mean by flows? That also matters.
Deepanjan Majumdar: So, first of all, tell me.
Deepanjan Majumdar: tenant workflows, right? I have seen…
PAUL: native workflows, if you should think about, the same thing, the idea is that you represent it through a meltdown or a moment. That's the main stuff.
Deepanjan Majumdar: But I've seen that, I've seen, you know, things with Claude, which can basically, with simple human English language, it can generate N10 workflows.
PAUL: In 18 workflows, then again, you have the dependency of those documents.
PAUL: simple workflows it can generate. I can ask Cloud or ChatGPT to generate me an innate workflow, and based on that, it will do. But again, you have that source, or the reference of truth. You have to do based on that.
Deepanjan Majumdar: So if I give that as a RAG tool to the agent…
PAUL: See, the idea is that when you ask somebody to do anything now, the LLM has seen anything.
PAUL: Really, with respect to your documentation, I don't think the LLTM has seen.
PAUL: That's the poor idea of keeping it in the data part.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, because directly, if you pass into text, because to give you a response, it needs limited chunks. I cannot say, can use the entire document.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Hmm.
PAUL: That's why I'm much more focused towards on that. Based on query, what will be the mapping to the chunks? Always think about that, okay? If I ask this, what are the top 4 chunks? Will I get the data? If I'm getting the data, okay, if I'm not getting it, it means that something is wrong.
PAUL: Query to your channels.
Deepanjan Majumdar: To do that, achieve this without a diagram, it would be… fine-dealing is something which we'll have to rely on otherwise, right?
PAUL: Fine-tuning is not required. There are things that you can do, but really, fine-tuning, without fine-tuning, you can achieve a decent level. Okay, with fine-tuning, yes, as you have domain-specific data, the results will be for sure better, but at least with RAG, I know, it will be a decent level retrieval system that you can bet.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Okay.
PAUL: Always remember, like, if you do fine-tuning, it will be the best solution.
PAUL: There is no doubt in that.
Deepanjan Majumdar: Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, next.
PAUL: Admin, admin, okay, looks like there are no more queries, okay? So now, anyone with respect to installation issues, anyone.
PAUL: Or got everybody done quickly?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Please upload handwritten notes, which you taught the day before your study. Every note is available. Okay, so, Satish Tiwal, please check Notion. Okay, so at any point of time, I add all the notes, it's not… I keep it. So, if I'm sharing with respect to Notion, okay?
PAUL: So, when you go into, like, exploring Langchain here, at the end of the day, all the PDF files are there, okay? Please…
PAUL: checked.
PAUL: Into your exploring land chain.
PAUL: Whoever having an issue with respect to installations, okay?
PAUL: I have issue with installation.
PAUL: Alright, get done.
PAUL: Installation issues, if you… Actually, I had… Where you got stuck?
Kiran Rathod: the requirement.txt, right? There, I'm not able to.
PAUL: Share your screen. Share your screen. Without sharing, it becomes very hard.
PAUL: Admin, there is no audio from your site, admin.
PAUL: Let's check.
PAUL: Please start sharing your screen.
Kiran Rathod: Yes.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah, here, this… I'm struck here only in the initial downloads.
PAUL: Hmm… what you are doing.
PAUL: PayPencil hyphen or requirement.txt. I told in the class, remove all the versions. Have you done it?
Kiran Rathod: For everything I need to remove? For all of them?
PAUL: That's the thing I told in class.
Kiran Rathod: Oh, okay.
Kiran Rathod: Let me try that, yeah.
PAUL: You have to remove all the versions, because those are Mac-based versions that I have. Once you remove it, it will work.
PAUL: And I'm using Docklin version 2.55.1. That's the only version specific, and the idea is to use the latest version of Blanchen.
Kiran Rathod: Okay, so let me come back on this, I'll try to install, reinstall, yeah.
Kiran Rathod: Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Alrighty guys, so look like no more berries for today. Okay, so let's conclude the session. Okay, and tomorrow we'll be talking about unstructured very specifically.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Fine, everyone.
PAUL: Why, why, thanks for joining.